American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIc. 1826-1836 APS.Archives.IIc APS.Archives.IIc
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - G[eorge] O[rd] to John Vaughan, August 13, 1831; 8" x 9 3/4"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Liverpool, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.Initialled. Forwards Audubon's Biography of American Birds, and Waterton's Wanderings to the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to J.K.Kane, Aug. 19, 1831; 10x8; Pereira de Azambuja, Jacob Frederico Torlade, 1788-1847
    Georgetown, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Forwards material from the Lisbon academy of science.
  - Nich[olas] Collin to John Vaughan, August 23, 1831; 6 1/2 x 8"; Collin, Nicholas, 1746-1831
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Wishes to pay his "last contribution" to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 24, 1831; 9x7-1/2; McLane, Louis, 1786-1857
    A.L.S. 2p. and end. Forwards papers from London.
  - Letter to Jonh [sic] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 2, 1831; 10x8; Tornel y Mendívil, José María, 1789-1853
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In Spanish. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 12, 1831; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    Copenhagen, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning donations.
  - Moses Thomas to the American Philosophical Society, September 12, 1831; 7 1/4" x 8 15/16"; Thomas, Moses
    Worcester, Mass., 2 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Concerning bequest of $500 by Isaiah Thomas to the A.P.S.; together with a set of the Massachusetts Spy from 1816 to 1830.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, September 18, 1831; 6 3/8" x 8"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. "I avail myself of the return of Mr. Ord to Philadelphia to send you some Brochures for the Philosophical Society."
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 19, 1831; 9x7-1/2; Brongniart, Alexandre, 1770-1847
    Paris, L.S. 2p.and add.,end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 20, 1831; 10x8; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Reuben Haines. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for casts of mastodon bones.
  - W[illiam] C. Rives to J[ohn] K. Kane, September 24, 1831; 8" x 10"; Rives, William C. (William Cabell), 1793-1868
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Paris, 2 pp. and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the A.P.S. together with the receipt of his certificate.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, Sept. 26, 1831; 10x8; Sagra, Ramón de la, 1798-1871
    Havana, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In Spanish. Forwards volume.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 26, 1831; 10x8; Tornel y Mendívil, José María, 1789-1853
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In Spanish. Concerning a shipment via New Orleans.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 27, 1831; 10x8; Shaler, William, 1778?-1833
    Havana, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards Sagra's gift. See letter from Sagra to the Secretary of the APS; Sept. 26, 1831.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 2, 1831; 10x8; Tornel y Mendívil, José María, 1789-1853
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. In Spanish. Thanks for publications. Leaves forwarding address.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the APS, Oct. 6, 1831; 9x8; Gonzalez, Francisco Antonio
    Madrid, L.S. 1p.and end. In Spanish. Acknowledges membership.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, October 10, 1831; 6 7/8" x 8 3/4"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., A.L.S. Has forwarded certain designated journals to Vaughan by M. Bertrand.
  - Letter to J[oh]n Vaughan, Oct. 20, 1831; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Bell, John, 1796-1872
  - Letter to J.K.Kane, Oct.20, 1831; 10x8; Navarrete, Martín Fernández de, 1765-1844
    Madrid, L.S. 1p.and end. In Spanish. Acknowledges membership certificate from the APS.
  - Letter to Major Hartman Bache, Oct. 21, 1831; 10" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in ms. S: J.K.Kane, secretary. 1p. and env. Announcing his election to membership. Presented by Miss Edith Bache, March 1954.
  - Hartman Bache to J[ohn] K. Kane, October 25, 1831; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Bache, Hartman, 1797-1872
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Moses Thomas to John Vaughan, October 26, 1831; 8" x 9 5/8"; Thomas, Moses
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Worcester, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Will pay $487.50 and forward box of newspapers to A.P.S., in accordance with will of Isaiah Thomas, upon return of receipt for same.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 27, 1831; 10-1/4x8; Wallenstein, Jules de, -1845
    Philadelphia, A.L. in 3rd P. 1p. and add. Return of books to A.P.S.
  - Richard C. Taylor to John Vaughan, October 29, 1831; 8" x 10"; Taylor, Richard C. (Richard Cowling), 1789-1851
    Athenaeum, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. R. Harlan, who wishes access to the cabinet of fossils "which remain at present in the Room of the Philosophical Society."
  - Report of committee on N[icholas] Collints paper on necrological observations, Nov. 4, 1831; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Isaac Hays, Willm. H. Keating, and J.K. Mitchell. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.620.
  - Report of committee on [Benjamin F.] Joslin's paper on irradiation, Nov. 4, 1831; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: A.D.Bache, Isaiah Lukens and C.Pickering. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.620. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., IV, 340 ff.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 30, 1831; 10x8; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    [Copenhagen,]. A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards volumes.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Nov., 1831; 10x8; Dannery, S.
    A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Forwards publication of Ramon de la Sagra.
  - Concerning a new species of fresh water tortoise, Dec. 1, 1831; 10x8; Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843
    D. 6p.and end. (see Ms.comm. to the APS. Natural history, vol. 2, no. 76.) Cf. Minutes, p.624.
  - Report of committee on [Isaac] Hays' paper on fossils, Dec. 16, 1831; 6x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Isaac Lea and C.Pickering. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.621. Printed: APS Proc., II, 105.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 19, 1831; 9-1/2x8; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    Batavia, L.S.: Van der Vinne. 3p. and end. In French. ----Copy. Forwards publications.
  - Baron de Ferussac to the Secretary of the A.P.S., December 24, 1831; 7 15/16" x 10 1/8"; Ferussac, André-Étienne-Just-Paschal-Joseph-François d'Audebard, baron de, 1786-1836
    Paris, 3 pp. Pr.L. Signed: Bar[on] de Ferussac. MS. notation. (In French.) Regarding continuation of his Histoire naturelle des Mollusques.
  - J[oh]n Vaughan to George Ord, December --, 1831; 7 7/8" x 12 1/2"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Dr., ----, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Unsigned. George Ord's bills for books purchased for the American Philosophical Society.
  - Concerning Mexican antiquities in the Society, [1831]; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Refers to a report by Mr. Warden on Mexican antiquities at the A.P.S., and finds it of sufficient interest (although it "leads to no result"), to recommend publication in the A.P.S. Transactions.
  - Condy Raguet to Peter S. DuPonceau, President of the A.P.S., January 2, 1832; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Raguet, Condy, 1784-1842
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: The Free Trade Advocate, 2 vols., 1829; and The Banner of the Constitution, 2 vols., 1830 and 1831.
  - W[illiam] Rawle to John K. Kane, January 3, 1832; 7 7/8" x 9 1/4"; Rawle, William, 1759-1836
    Secretary of the A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: a lithographic print of Chief Justice [John] Marshall.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 5, 1832; 10x8; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. Encloses a toast to be given in his name at the APS meeting: "...when Franklins on Franklins shall arise..." FILM54-67 FRAME 71
  - Report of committee on making casts of mastodon bones, [Jan. 20, 1832]; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p., receipted by John Chitty; witnessed by J. Snider, jr., end., and end. Cf. Minutes, p.622.
  - H[enry] D. Gilpin to John K. Kane, January 20, 1832; 7 15/16" x 9 3/4"; Gilpin, Henry D. (Henry Dilworth), 1801-1860
  - Steen Billé to J[ohn] K. Kane, January 21, 1832; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Bille, Steen, 1797-1883
    Secretary to the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - J[ulius] T. Ducatel to J[ohn] K. Kane, January 24, 1832; 7 15/16" x 9 15/16"; Ducatel, Julius Timoleon, 1796-1849
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Baltimore, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of his certificate of membership in the A.P.S.
  - Tho[mas] Sergeant to J[ohn] K. Kane, January 24, 1832; 8" x 10"; Sergeant, Thomas, 1782-1860
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Jan. 30, 1832; 10x8; Bataafsch Genootschap der Proefondervindelijke Wijsbegeerte (Rotterdam, Netherlands)
    Philadelphia, Rotterdam, L.S.: C. J.Glaimans. 1p.and end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the President and members of the APS, Jan. 30, 1832; 8" x 12 1/2"; Dannery, S.
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. and enc. - 2p. Theft of medals from the Bibliothéque duRoi, Paris, on Nov. 5 and 6, 1831. Encloses list of them.
  - Letter to J[ohn] K. Kane, Feb. 13, 1832; 10x8; Tanner, Henry Schenck, 1786-1858
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning the publication of an article by E.C.Bridgman.
  - Report of committee on Manilla [sic] by E.C. Bridgman, Feb. 17, 1832; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: J.K.Kane. 1p.,end.
  - Geo[rge] Vaux to John Vaughan, February 27, 1832; 7 13/16" x 9 7/8"; Vaux, George
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning a decline in the price of books in Paris. Cites as an example, the work of the Egyptian Institute.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Feb., 1832; 10x8; Athenaeum of Philadelphia
    L.S.: Wm. Smith, Roberts Vaux, Saml.Norris, and Jos. Gratz. 1p.and add.,end. Enc. Wishes to meet with the APS committee on the library. For enclosure: see Athenaeum minutes; Feb. 13, 1832.
  - W[illia]m Shaler to John Vaughan, March 5, 1832; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Shaler, William, 1778?-1833
    Havana, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: Havana Almanack, 1832; and the two last numbers of the Cuban Review.
  - H[enry] Ware, Jr., to John Vaughan, March 6, 1832; 7 1/4" x 9"; Ware, Henry, 1794-1843
    Cambridge, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Letter of inquiry regarding location of [Joseph] Priestley letters.
  - Letter to [John Vaugahn], March 16, 1832; 12-1/2x8; Roux de Rochelle, 1762-1849
    Paris, L.S. 3p.and end. In French. "Copie." Forwards publications and list of publications from the French academy and institute.
  - Letter to A.P.S., 1832 March 16; Say, Benjamin, 1755-1813
    Note that states Benjamin Say deposited the original deed between John Fitch and various Philadelphia citizens dated February 9, 1787 crating a joint stock company for propelling vessels through the water by the agency of steam.
  - A. H. L. Heeren to Peter S. DuPonceau, March 23, 1832; 7 13/16" x 9 7/8"; Heeren, A. H. L. (Arnold Hermann Ludwig), 1760-1842
    President of the A.P.S., Göttingen, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of [William B.] Hodgson's dissertation on the Berber language. Its value. English translation of Heeren's work. FILM403 FRAME116
  - John C. Warren to John Vaughan, March 23, 1832; 8 1/8" x 10 1/16"; Warren, John Collins, 1778-1856
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. J[ames] S. Sullivan, son of General [William] Sullivan. Acknowledges receipt of last number of A.P.S. publications.
  - R. D. Greene to John Vaughan, March 24, 1832; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Greene, R. D.
    Boston, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Wishes to subscribe to A.P.S. Trans. IV. Is sailing from Boston for Charleston. Will see Vaughan at Philadelphia upon his return trip.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, March 24, 1832; 6 3/4" x 8 3/4"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards six volumes of Academy of Inscriptions to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 28, 1832; 9-1/2x8; American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    Boston, A.L.S.: F.C. Gray. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], March 29, 1832; 10x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Josiah Quincy and Thaddeus William Harris. 1p. and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Pierre DuPonceau, April 4, 1832; 10x8; Pereira de Azambuja, Jacob Frederico Torlade, 1788-1847
    Georgetown, A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., April 10, 1832; 10x7; Naccari, Fortunato Luigi
    Chioggia, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. Enc. Forwards volume on order of Charles Lucien Bonaparte. For enc.,see: Naccari. Dedication...; April 10, 1832.
  - Dedication to the APS of his Flora Veneta, April 10, 1832; 10x7; Naccari, Fortunato Luigi
    A.D.S. 1p. and end."...sent to Chas.Luc. Bonaparte..." In Italian. Enclosed originally in letter from Naccaria to the APS; April 10, 1832
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 13, 1832; 8x5; Browne, Peter A. (Peter Arrell), 1782-1860
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. and end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to P[eter S.] DuPonceau, Philadelphia, April 14, 1832; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Moore, George
    Trieste, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards package.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 19, 1832; 10x8; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Concerning Mr. Torlade of Portugual. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 21, 1832; 10x8; Quadrado y de Roó, Francisco de Paula
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Forwards publications of the royal academy of history of Madrid. Thanks for making Martinez a member of the APS.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, secretary of the A.P.S., April 24, 1832; 8" x 10"; Martínez, Juan José
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Acknowledges election to membership. Cf. Minutes, April 20, 1832.
  - S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton to Jno. Vaughan, April 24, 1832; 4 7/8" x 8 1/8"; Morton, Samuel George, 1799-1851
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding a collection of antique Peruvian vessels deposited in his care, for the A.P.S., by Dr. Burrough.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, secretary of A.P.S., April 27, 1832; 7 3/4" x 10"; Hodge, Hugh L. (Hugh Lenox), 1796-1873
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Acknowledges election to membership.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 28, 1832; 10x8; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Mentions Roux de Rochelle,who might be made a member.
  - John J. Abert to F[ranklin] Bache, May 2, 1832; 7 15/16" x 9 13/16"; Abert, John James, 1788-1863
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Washington, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - H[enry] J[ames] Anderson to Jno. Vaughan, May 2, 1832; 8" x 9 11/16"; Anderson, Henry J. (Henry James), 1799-1875
    Librarian of the A.P.S., New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning subscribers [to A.P.S. Transactions] in New York.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, May 3, 1832; 13-1/2x9; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edward Turner. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, May 4, 1832; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
    Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Nich[ola]s Carlisle. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, May 11, 1832; 9x7-1/2; Royal Astronomical Society
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: A.Lee Morgan. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Peter S. DuPonceau to John Vaughan, May 21, 1832; 8" x 10"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Washington, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Plan for making A.P.S. "the center of scientific communication between the new world and the old."
  - Letter to George Ord, Philadelphia, May 24, 1832; 9x7-1/2; Linnean Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S: F. Boott. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 24, 1832; 9x7; London Institution
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm. Maltby. 1p. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., May, 1832; 10x8; Coraboeuf,
    Paris, L.S. 1p.and end. In French. Donates volume.
  - List of publications of the société, May, 1832; 10x8; Société asiatique (Paris, France)
    D.S.: Cassin. In French. Enclosed originally in letter from the société asiatique to the Sec. of the APS; June 9, 1832.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 5, 1832; 10x8; Hayes, S.
    West Point, A.L.S. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for publications and orders others.
  - Peter S. DuPonceau to John Vaughan, June 9, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Encloses a copy or a letter from A. H. L. Heeren, of Göttingen, with a request that it be read at the next meeting of the Society. FILM403 FRAME 106
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., June 9, 1832; 10x8; Société asiatique (Paris, France)
    Paris, L.S.: Eug[en]e Burnouf. 1p. and end. In French. Enc. ---Copy with letter from DuPonceau to J. Vaughan; Oct. 1, 1835. Desires to exchange publications. Forwards their publications.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, secretary of A.P.S., June 10, 1832; 8" x 9 3/4"; Lorin, Theodore Quentin, 1775-1857
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add. and end. In French. Acknowledges membership in the Society, and receipt of certificate.
  - Letter to Juan Vaughan, June 16, 1832; 8x6; Real Academia de la Historia
    Madrid, L.S.: Diego Clemencin. 1p.and end. In Spanish. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 2, 1832; 10-1/2x8; Société asiatique (Paris, France)
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Eug. Burnouf. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to W[illiam] Vaughan, London, July 5, 1832; 9x7-1/2; Royal Dublin Society
    L.S.: Fred. Cradoch. 1p.,end. ----Copy. Thanks for APS publications. On same sheet is letter from Cradoch to W. Vaughan; July 7, 1832.
  - Peter S. DuPonceau to John Vaughan, July 6, 1832; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S., a copper coin bearing the likeness of George Washington, dated 1791.
  - Letter to W[illiam] Vaughan, July 7, 1832; 9X7-1/2, 10x8; Caradoc, Sir John Francis, 1762-1839
    A.L.S. 1p. ----Copy. Asks for naides of the US be forwarded to him, as described in APS publication. On same sheet as Royal Dublin society to W.Vaughan; July 5, 1832.
  - Letter to Dr. Chapman, July 8, 1832; 10x8-1/2; Joseph Bonaparte, King of Spain, 1768-1844
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. In French. Forwards publication. FILM403 FRAME 179
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., July 9, 1832; 10x8; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, L.S.: J. Arago. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., July 10, 1832; 10x8; Société de géographie (France)
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Jomard. 1p.and end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., July 11, 1832; 10X7-1/2; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, L.S.: F. Arago. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to David B. Warden, [1832] July 12; De Bure feres
    Concerning books for the A.P.S..
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 13, 1832; 10x8; Pickering, John, 1777-1846
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Friendly letter.
  - Statement of shipment to John Vaughan, July 15, 1832; 10-1/2x8; Eyriès, Alexandre
    Havre, D.S. 1p.,end.by receipt by Peter S. DuPonceau, and end. In French. Books for the society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 17, 1832; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Debure frères
    Paris, L. 2p. In French. "Duplicata" Reports of purchases to the APS.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 17, 1832; 10x7-1/2; Debure frères
    Paris, L.S. 2p.and add.,end. In French. Sends list of books purchased for the APS in Paris. On same sheet is note by Vaughan stating the numbers of books sent to theAPS; Sept. 7, 1832.
  - Letter to [David Bailie] Warden, Paris, July 17, 1832; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Debure frères
    Paris, L. 1p. In French. Has reported to Vaughan of the purchases for the A.P.S.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, July 17, 1832; 6 3/4" x 8 3/4"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has forwarded case [of books] to the A.P.S. Has distributed A.P.S. Transactions, IV, pt. 1.
  - J[ohn] Q[uincy] Adams to John Vaughan, July 19, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S. some minerals received from Andrew Armstrong in Peru.
  - Bar[on] de Ferussac to the Secretary of the A.P.S., July 21, 1832; 8" x 10"; Ferussac, André-Étienne-Just-Paschal-Joseph-François d'Audebard, baron de, 1786-1836
    Paris, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Regarding books for the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 31, 1832; 10x8; Larne and Palmer
    Havre, L. 1p. and add., end. Shipped carton to the APS.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 1, 1832; 8x6; Real Academia de la Historia
    Madrid, L.S.: Diego Clemencin. 1p. and end. In Spanish. forwards volume.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 4, 1832; 10x8; Schweinitz, Lewis David von, 1780-1834
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - H. Bry to P[eter] S. DuPonceau, August 6, 1832; 8" x 10"; Bry, H.
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents Mr. DuPonceau with a piece of silk woven by worms at his own home.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, librarian of A.P.S., Aug. 12/24, 1832; 7 1/2" x 9 1/4"; Buchanan, James, 1791-1868
    St. Petersburg, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Packet delivered safely to Count Nesselrode. Forwards package from the Imperial academy of sciences, St. Petersburg.
  - Christopher Columbus Baldwin to John Vaughan, August 30, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 15/16"; Baldwin, Christopher Columbus, 1800-1835
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Worcester, Mass., 3pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The origin, purpose, and work of the American Antiquarian Society. Suggests an exchange of duplicates.
  - Note stating the number of books sent to the APS by De Brure freres, Sept. 7, 1832; 10x7-1/2; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, A.N.S. 1p. On same sheet as letter from De Brure freres to J.Vaughan; July 17, 1832.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Sept. 12, 1832; 10x8; Dallas, George Mifflin, 1792-1864
    A.L.S. 1p. and end. Donates volumes.
  - Peter S. DuPonceau to John Vaughan, September 12, 1832; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 4 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Failure of silk bill in Congress. Mr. Bellati. Possibility of silk culture in the south.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 13, 1832; 10-1/2x8; Kungl. Svenska vetenskapsakademien
    Stockholm, L.S.: Berzelius. (Signature missing, but note explains why it was removed.) 1p. and end. Thanks for publication.